特
特效
特效字
特效字幕
特效字幕制
特效字幕制作
特效字幕制作：
特效字幕制作：5
特效字幕制作：52
特效字幕制作：520
特效字幕制作：520c
特效字幕制作：520co
特效字幕制作：520coo
特效字幕制作：520cool
幸福终点站
联合航空公司 从北京返回的9435号班机已经到达
United Airlines announcing the arrival of Flight 9435 from Beijing.
旅客服务代表请到c42号门
Customer service representative, report to Gate C42.
所有来访美国的游客 请在15号通道1号厅排好队
All visitors to the US should line up at booths one through 15.
请大家填写好I-94卡
Please have your l-94 forms filled out.
-你来访的目的是什么?  -你来访的目的是什么?
-What's the purpose of your visit?  -What is the purpose of your visit?
你来访的目的是什么? 公事还是私事?
What is the purpose of your visit? Business or pleasure?
只是旅游 购物
Just visiting. Shopping?
旅游
Au plaisir.
-私事  -公事
-Pleasure.  -Business.
你会逗留多久?
How long will you be staying?
能出示您的回程机票吗?
Could I see your return ticket?
-你来访的目的是什么?  -公事还是私事?
-What's the purpose of your visit?  -Business or pleasure?
旅程愉快 下一个
Enjoy your stay. Next.
请准备好您的护照 I-94移民申请表
Please have your passports, immigration forms, l-94,
以及通关申报表等待核查
and customs declarations ready to hand to the inspector.
-注意了 有情况  -明白
-Stand by. He's fishing.  -Copy that.
你看到这些穿米老鼠T恤的人吗?
See this bunch of Mickey Mouse sweatshirts?
他们是中国来的游客 转机到奥兰多
That's the tour from China, connecting to Orlando.
你上一次看到中国旅游团
When was the last time you saw Chinese tourists
去迪斯尼乐园却没有一台照相机是什么时候?
on their way to Disney World without any cameras?
在10号11号通道可能有伪造证件
Possible forged documents on 10 and 11.
先生 先生 护照
Sir. Sir. Passport.
谢谢
Thank you.
欢迎您纳沃斯基先生
Welcome, Mr Navorski.
您来访的目的?
Purpose of your visit?
公事还是私事
Business or pleasure?
[保加利亚语]
[Speaks Bulgarian]
头儿 我这里系统出问题了
Sir, I have an IBIS hit on six.
不要!
No!
纳沃斯基先生 请跟我来
Mr Navorski, please follow me.
从蒙特利尔返航的746班机
... flight number 746 from Montreal
在领取行李前必须先到移民登记处审察
must proceed to US Immigration before claiming their luggage.
好的 纳沃斯基先生 请你在这里稍等
All right, Mr Navorski, we'd like you to wait here, please.
下一位
Next, please.
你来美国做什么 纳沃斯基先生
What are you doing in the United States, Mr Navorski?
我要黄色的出租车
Yellow taxicab, please.
带我去罗玛达酒店
Take me to Ramada Inn,
列克星敦161号
161 Lexington.
您打算住在罗玛达酒店?
Staying at the Ramada Inn?
不用找零钱了
Keep the change.
你在纽约有熟人吗?
Do you know anyone in New York?
是的
Yes.
-谁?  -是的
-Who?  -Yes.
-不是 你在纽约有认识的人吗?  -是的
-No, do you know anyone in New York?  -Yes.
-谁?  -是的
-Who?  -Yes.
列克星敦161号
161 Lexington.
好了 纳沃斯基先生 我需要看你的回程机票
OK, Mr Navorski, I need to see your return ticket, please.
不 你的回程机票 你的
No, your return ticket. Your...
是的
Oh... Yes.
只是例行公事而已
This is just a standard procedure.
还有你的护照
I'm going to need the passport also.
好的
Oh... OK.
-不 不是  -谢谢
-No, no.  -Thank you.
纳沃斯基先生
Mr Navorski.
那个 护照
That. Passport.
对
That.
纳沃斯基先生 让您久等了
Mr Navorski? Sorry to keep you waiting.
我是弗兰克·狄克逊
I'm Frank Dixon
我是肯尼迪机场 美国海关及边境保护局的主管
Director of Customs and Border Protection here at JFK.
我帮助外国人解决入境问题
I help people with their immigration problems.
我们在为你寻找翻译
We're looking for an interpreter for you.
怎么样了? 我们有翻译吗?
How are we doing on that? Do we have an interpreter?
不过我知道你会说一点英语
But I understand that you speak a little English.
-是的  -是吗?
-Yes.  -You do?
希望你不介意我在谈话的时候吃东西 我有些坏消息
I hope you don't mind if I eat while we talk. I've a bit of bad news.
你们国家政府发布的护照
Your country has suspended all travelling privileges
已经暂停使用了
on passports issued by your government.
你所持有的进入美国的签证
And our State Department has revoked the visa
已经被我国国务院注销了
that was going to allow you to enter the US.
简而言之就是这样
That's it in a nutshell, basically.
当您还在飞机上的时候 你们国家爆发了军事政变
While you were in the air there was a military coup in your country.
很多总统护卫已经身亡
Most of the dead were members of the Presidential Guard.
他们是在午夜发动袭击的
They were attacked in the middle of the night.
交火非常激烈
They got it all on GHN, I think.
只有很少的平民伤亡 我相信你的家人都没事
There were few civilian casualties. I'm sure your family's fine.
纳沃斯基先生 你们国家内部出现政变了
Mr Navorski, your country was annexed from the inside.
卡科日亚共和国有了新的领导层
The Republic of Krakozhia is under new leadership.
卡科日亚 卡科日亚
Krakozhia. Krakozhia
-卡科日亚  -我想他没听明白
-Krakozhia.  -Right. I don't think he gets it.
恩 让我 看这里
Er... Let me... OK. Look.
把这些薯片当作卡科日亚
Imagine that these potato chips are Krakozhia.
卡科-日亚
Kra-kozhia.
-卡科-日亚  -是的
-Kra-kozhia.  -Yes.
-卡科日亚  -好的
-Krakozhia.  -OK.
恩 现在薯片就是卡科日亚
Er... So the potato chips are Krakozhia.
-然后这个苹果  -大苹果 大苹果
-And this apple...  -Big Apple. Big Apple.
大苹果代表叛乱分子
...Big Apple represents the Liberty Rebels.
明白吗?
OK?
再没有卡科日亚了!知道吗?
No more Krakozhia! OK?
新的政府 革命 你明白吗?
New government. Revolution. You understand?
所有进出你们国家的航班都已经停飞了
All the flights in and out of your country have been suspended.
新的政府封锁了所有的边境 所以你的签证已经作废了
The new government has sealed all borders, so your visa's no longer valid.
你现在是没有国家的公民
So, currently you are a citizen of nowhere.
我们无法给你申请新的签证
Now, we can't process you new papers
直到美国政府和你们国家的新政府重新建立外交关系
until the US recognizes your country's new diplomatic reclassification.
你不享有庇护权 难民身份权
You don't qualify for asylum, refugee status,
临时保护权 人道主义特许入境
temporary protective status, humanitarian parole,
或者工作 旅游签证 你都不符合资格
or non-immigration work travel. You don't qualify for any of these.
简单的说你现在是
You are at this time simply...
无法接受的人  -无法接受的人
...unacceptable.  -Unacceptable.
-无法接受  -无法接受
-Unacceptable.  -Unacceptable.
我这次旅行包括布鲁克林大桥
Big Apple tour includes Brooklyn Bridge
帝国大厦 百老汇名剧"猫"
Empire State, Broadway show Cats.
还有更多的坏消息 "猫"停演了
I got more bad news for you. Cats has closed.
好的 好的
OK. OK.
现在我能去纽约了吧 谢谢
Now I go New York City. Thank you.
不行 纳沃斯基先生 我现在不能让你进入美国
No, Mr Navorski. I cannot allow you to enter the United States at this time.
-卡科日亚  -我们也无法让你回家
-Krakozhia.  -We can't allow you to go home either.
你没有真正的家了 理论上已经不存在了
You don't really have a home. Technically it doesn't exist.
就像"阴阳魔界" 你看过这部电视剧吗?
It's like a Twilight Zone. Do you get that show over there?
蒂娜 扎蒂米斯菲特
Talking Tina, Zanti Misfits.
扎蒂米斯菲特是"超越极限"的主角
Zanti Misfits was Outer Limits, sir.
真的吗?不重要了
Really? It's not important.
我在那里能买到耐克运动鞋
Where do I buy the Nike shoes?
纳沃斯基先生 过来
OK, Mr Navorski, come here.
现在我真是进退二难 纳沃斯基先生
Here's my dilemma, Mr Navorski.
你没有权利进入美国 但是我也没有权利拘留你
You have no right to enter the US and I have no right to detain you.
入境的最大特例给你碰上了
You have fallen through a crack in the system.
-我是特例  -是的 直到我们解决好前
-I am crack.  -Yes. Until we get this sorted out
我会允许你进入国际候机大厅
I will allow you to enter the International Transit Lounge.
我会帮你填写一张保证书 允许你自由活动
I'm going to sign a release form that is going to make you a free man.
-自由?  -自由 自由
-Free?  -Free. Free.
在国际候机大厅自由活动
Free to go anywhere you like in the International Transit Lounge.
-好吗?  -好的
-OK?  -OK.
-好的  -好的
-OK.  -OK.
好
OK.
美国政府明天就会处理好这些麻烦
Uncle Sam will have this sorted out by tomorrow,
欢迎您"基本上"来到美国
and welcome to the United States. Almost.
-谢谢  -好的
-Thank you.  -OK. All right.
麻烦了 法官
Thanks, Judge.
来自新加坡的76号航班已经抵达
Announcing the arrival of flight 76 from Singapore Airlines.
纳沃斯基先生
Now, Mr Navorski.
纳沃斯基先生 纳沃斯基先生
Mr Navorski. Mr Navorski.
这里就是国际候机大厅
This is the International Transit Lounge.
你可以在这里自由活动 这些是食物购买券
You are free to wait here. These are food vouchers.
你可以在那边的食堂使用
You can use them in the Food Court.
你的卡科日亚币在这里无法使用
Your Krakozhian money is no good here.
这是张已经预付15分钟话费的电话卡
This is a 15-minute, prepaid calling card.
如果你需要 可以打电话回家
You may call home, if you like.
这个传呼机 是我们联系你的方式
This, in case we need to contact you, is a pager.
你必须时刻携带
You must keep this with you at all times.
这个ID卡是给你进入美海关与边境保护局的 这些门前面
Here is an ID badge for you to get into CBP. Beyond those doors...
纳沃斯基先生 请您看着我
Mr Navorski. I'm going to need you to look at me.
这些门前面就是美国领土
Beyond those doors is American soil.
狄克逊先生希望讲清楚
Mr Dixon wants me to make it clear
你不能穿过这些门
that you are not to enter through those doors.
你不能离开这栋建筑 美国对你关闭了
You are not to leave this building. America is closed.
美国关闭了
America closed.
我该做什么?
What I do?
你在这里只能做一件事 纳沃斯基先生
There's only one thing you can do here, Mr Navorski.
购物
Shop.
纽约至华沙的854班机的乘客
Passengers of flight 854 New York/Warsaw...
国际组织正试图 通过和平方式解决
... the international community tries to secure a peaceful resolution.
平民们希望能有稳定的政治环境
The populace has to wonder if they will ever find political stability,
或者新的领导者能保证他们的国际地位
or find the leadership to secure their place on the world stage.
接下来为您介绍最新的游艇
And next this hour, looking to buy a 90-foot yacht?
挟持人质 有消息报道副总统 以及4位内阁成员已经身亡
... taken hostage. We're hearing that the Vice President has been killed
13位士兵和20位市民在冲突中受伤
along with four cabinet members, 13 injured soldiers and 20 civilians.
凌晨时分 叛军已经包围首府官邸
By dawn, rebel leaders had surrounded the state houses.
作为国家标志的卡科日亚国旗
In a symbolic gesture, the national flag of Krakozhia was torn down
已经从总统官邸和国会大厦被撕下
from the Presidential Palace and the parliament building.
请 帮我
Please. Please.
电视
Television.
乘客陈婉舒书和刘涛锦
Passenger Chen Wan-Shiu and Liu Tao-Jing,
请到指挥台领取登机证
please come to podium to pick up your boarding passes.
最新消息
This just in.
昨晚的军事政变 推翻了卡科日亚政府
Last night a military coup overthrew the government of Krakozhia.
整夜四处都是爆炸声和枪声
Bombing and gunfire were heard through the night.
虽然具体情况还不是很清楚
Although details are unclear,
总统和副官
we are told that President Vagobagin…
已经被挟持为人质
…and his aides have been taken hostage.
先生 你是红地毯俱乐部会员吗?
Bonjour, monsieur. You are a Red Carpet Club member?
请出示您的登机证和会员卡 先生
I need to see your boarding pass and club card, sir.
对不起 先生 这是私人候机室
I'm sorry, sir. This is a private lounge.
公共候机室在楼下
The public lounge is downstairs.
这个本地区人口最少的国家 又经历了一次劫难
The tiniest nation in the region has been shaken by another uprising.
卡科日亚自从社会主义瓦解转型以来
Krakozhia has been involved in civil war throughout the late '80s and '90s
在80至90年代一直处在内战状态
as it has tried to transition from Communist rule.
-没长眼睛啊!  -帮我
-Watch it!  -Please.
帮我 电话? 电话?
Please, telephone? Telephone?
电话?
Telephone?
帮我 帮我
Please. Please.
出于安全原因请您照看好您的行李
For security reasons, please keep your luggage with you at all times.
无人看管的行李会被收集检查甚至销毁
Unattended luggage will be removed for inspection and may be destroyed.
我的天 我的天啊 你弄坏了我的包!
Oh, my God. Oh, my God, you broke my bag!
我从巴黎买的 这是我最喜欢的包
I got this in Paris. This is my favourite bag.
真不敢相信被你弄坏了! 爸 妈!他弄坏了我的包
I can't believe you just broke my bag! Mom, Dad! He broke my bag!
-食物券  -对不起 住手 住手
-Food document.  -Excuse me. Stop it. Stop it.
请问你有预约吗?
Do you have an appointment?
我不会让任何人没有预约就翻看我的垃圾
I don't let anyone to look at my trash without an appointment.
我下个星期二才有空
I have an opening next Tuesday.
星期二 星期二 星期一 星期二 星期三 星期四
Tuesday. Tuesday, Monday, Tuesday, Wednesday, Tuesday.
那时候你可以过来找你丢失的东西
It will be good time for you to come back and get lost.
好的 再见 不好意思
OK, goodbye. Sorry.
星期二
Tuesday.
不要开枪
Don't shoot!
它有12张床位 弗兰克 120伏的发电机 小酒吧 瓦斯设备
She sleeps 12, Frank. Has a 120-volt generator, wet bar, gas range.
她太迷人了
She looks amazing.
她简直就是我梦中情人
She's my pot of gold at the end of the rainbow.
她是艘很漂亮的船 希望你能尽快得到她
She's a beautiful boat and I hope you get her soon.
-你挣的已经不少了  -谢谢你 弗兰克
-You've earned her.  -Thank you, Frank.
-你当之无愧  -实际上 我昨天已经买下它了
-You have.  -Actually, I bought her yesterday.
天啊 祝贺你!
Come on. Congratulations!
我推荐你顶替我的职位
I'm nominating you to take my place.
等华盛顿批准以后
You will assume the duties of acting Field Commissioner
你就是地区委任专员了
until you get approval from Washington.
真的吗?我真不知道该说什么了
Really? I don't know what to say.
-天啊 理查德 真的吗?  -真的 弗兰克 是真的
-Jesus. Richard, is this real?  -It's real, Frank, it's real.
不要装得这么惊讶
Don't pretend to be surprised.
你已经等我退休或者暴毙很久了吧
You've been waiting for me to retire or drop dead for years now.
不 我没有等着你退休
No, I haven't been waiting for you to retire.
好的 弗兰克
That's all right, Frank.
我退休那天就是你上任的日子
My retirement will become official the day you get sworn in.
-你已经等这天很久了  -是的
-You've waited a long time for this.  -I have.
应付好考察程序
Just be careful about the inspection process.
我会的 我在这里工作17年了
I will. I've been here for 17 years...
我们在谈论地区专员的责任
We're talking about the Field Commissioner position.
大家希望有你的领导 有一个榜样
People are going to look to you for leadership, to set an example.
你在说什么?
What are you saying?
我说这工作非你莫属
I'm saying the job is yours to lose.
把哥伦比亚人送到收容所
Ship the Colombians off to asylum hearings,
联系他们在长岛的父母
and call the parents of those kids from Long Island.
告诉他们去牙买加不是个好主意
Tell them it was a bad idea to let them go to Jamaica.
来吧 行动起来 去南美和马德里的飞机已经准备起飞了
Come on, let's go. South America and Madrid are on the tarmac.
我要他们在半个小时之内离开这里
I want them out of here in half an hour.
瑟曼先生
Mr Thurman.
大厅里有个穿着睡衣的男人在游荡
There's a man walking around the terminal in a bathrobe.
我知道 先生 你把他放在这儿的
I know, sir. You put him there.
欢迎来到美国
Welcome to the United States.
下一位!
Next!
我需要签证
I need visa.
你的绿色申请表呢? 没有表我无法工作
Where's your green form? I can't do anything without it.
去墙那边拿
Go to the wall.
下一位!
Next!
先生
Sir.
浅绿色申请表
The light green form.
我爱纽约
I love New York...
-我爱它!  -纽约
-I love it!  -New York
我爱纽约
I love New York
I love New York...
浅绿色
Light green.
纳沃斯基先生 没有签证是不能进入纽约的
Mr Navorski, you cannot get into New York without a visa.
没有护照就申请不到签证
You cannot get a visa without a passport,
没有国家就没有新的护照
and you cannot get a new passport without a country.
我们真的无能为力
There's nothing we can do for you here.
我给了你小绿色表
I give you light green.
对不起 你是在浪费时间
I'm sorry, but you've wasted an entire day.
现在你简单来说就是
At this time you are simply...
-无法接受  -是的
-Unacceptable.  -Yes.
无法接受
Unacceptable.
为什么他还在这里?
Why is he still here?
你允许的 先生 你让他在这里
You released him, sir. You put him there.
为什么他不走出那道门? 为什么他不逃走?
Why doesn't he walk out the doors? Why doesn't he try to escape?
-先生 是你让他等的  -我没想到他真的会等
-Sir, you told him to wait.  -I didn't think he'd actually do it.
我是说 他只是特殊情况 谁会这么死脑筋
I mean, he's in a crack. Who the hell waits in a crack?
国务院没有新的消息 不过我们可以在几天后把他驱逐出境
No news from the State Department, but we can deport him in a few days.
是的 可能是几天 也可能是几个星期 几个月
Yeah, it could be a few days. It could be a week, two weeks, a month.
谁知道他到底想些什么 他到底从那个集中营跑出来的
Who knows what this guy is thinking, what gulag he escaped from.
下一位
Next!
他做的所有事情都报告给我
Everything he does comes back to me.
你要把他管制起来吗?
You want him back in the holding cell?
不 我告诉他怎么出去
No, I'll show him the door.
你好
Hello.
-你有预约吗?  -是的 9.30
-Do you have an appointment?  -Yes. 9.30.
食物券 垃圾 星期二
Food document, trash. Tuesday.
星期二 我讨厌星期二
Tuesday. I hate the Tuesday.
对不起
Excuse me.
机场是很重要的地方 纳沃斯基先生
Airports are tricky places, Mr Navorski.
我要告诉你一些事情
I'm about to tell you something.
一些你永远不要告诉他人的事
Something you can never repeat to anyone.
你知道吗?这是机密
Do you understand? It's a secret.
-机密?  -是的 机密
-Secret?  -Yes, a secret.
中午12点这些门的守卫会离开岗位
At 12 o'clock today, the guards at those doors will leave their posts
换班的警卫会在5分钟后来
and their replacements are going to be five minutes late.
5分钟后
Late five minutes.
是的 12点过5分后来 只有今天 只有这一次
Yes. Late five minutes. At 12 o'clock. Just today. Just this once.
没有人会守卫这些大门
No one is going to be watching those doors.
-而且没有人会看到你  -所以美国没有关闭
-And no one will be watching you.  -So, America not closed.
没有
No.
美国这5分钟是开启的
America, for five minutes, is open.
祝你过的愉快 纳沃斯基先生
Have a nice life, Mr Navorski.
抓住 放开 很容易 有时候你抓到一条小鱼
Catch and release. It's simple. Sometimes you land a small fish.
你取下它然后放回水里
You unhook him and place him back in the water.
你让它自由 所以其它人 也可以享受钓鱼的乐趣
You set him free so that somebody else can have the pleasure of catching him.
好的 开始吧
All right, here we go.
好的 让他们离开
OK. Call them off.
詹森 离开大门
Johnson, clear the doors.
好的 走吧
All right. Go.
离开这里 好的 门没问题了
Get out of there. All right, there's the door.
好的
All right.
开始了 他现在在那里?
Here we go. Now where is he?
-他在这里  -不 不是他
-There he is.  -No, that's not him.
他在这里
There he is.
好的 维克多
All right, Viktor.
我们走吧
Here we go.
有什么复杂的?离开 维克多
What's so complicated? Exit, Viktor.
走吧 过几分钟后 你就是别人的麻烦了
Come on. In a few minutes, you'll be somebody else's problem.
他在确认没有人注意他
He wants to make sure nobody's watching.
我告诉过他没有人会看到他
I told him nobody would be watching.
走吧 好的 走
Come on. All right, here we go.
-通知机场警察  -已经去通知了
-Call the Airport Police.  -He's on his way.
对不起
Excuse me.
好的 快走吧
You got it. There we go.
他在等起跑信号吗?
He's got to get a running start, I guess.
走吧 走吧
Just leave. Just leave.
走 走
Leave. Leave.
你在做什么? 他为什么跪下了?他在祈祷吗?
What are you doing? Why is he kneeling? Is he praying?
不 他在系鞋带
No. He's tying his shoelace.
拜托 走吧
Come on, leave.
移开摄像头
Get the cameras.
他人呢?他人呢?
Where is he? Where is he?
-左边  -不是 他在门边上
-To the left of here.  -No. He was at the door.
-就在左边一点  -好的 好的
-Just go a little left.  -All right. All right.
我等着
I wait.
你们在看什么? 回去工作 谢谢
What are you looking at? Go back to work. Thank you.
天啊 倒霉
Oh, God. Oh, shit.
-这是你的吗?  -谢谢
-This belong you?  -Thank you.
真倒霉
Oh, shit.
看到吗?小心湿滑
See? Wet floor.
这就你
That you.
我要迟到了
I'm so late.
去阿根廷的航班 我不记得几号登机门了
Buenos Aires. I can't remember the gate.
24号门
Gate 24.
-你肯定吗?  -是的
-You sure?  -Yes.
谢谢
Thanks.
各位先生女士
Ladies and gentlemen...
等一下
Wait.
给你的 免费的鞋子
For you. Payless Shoes.
二楼 舒服的后跟
Second floor. Sensible heels.
-你好 宝贝  -过来
-Hi, baby.  -Come here, you.
我想他是CIA CIA派他来监视我们的
I think he's CIA. The CIA put him here to spy on us.
你在胡说些什么 他连英语都不会说
You don't know what you're talking about. He doesn't speak English.
他是装的
If he could learn to speak, this guy.
如果他不会说英语 他怎么能勾搭上那个漂亮小姐
He can't speak English, how could he have a meeting with a beautiful woman?
一个空中小姐
A flight attendant.
-那么她也是CIA  -不是
-So, she's CIA, too?  -No.
她看起来像是俄国人 克格勃 她把鞋根给他了
She look like a Russian. KGB. She gave him heel of her shoes.
然后他给了她一张纸条
And he gave her a piece of the paper.
-是缩微胶片萎缩价吗?  -免费鞋店的优惠券
-Was it microfilm?  -A coupon from Payless Shoes.
一定是什么密码
Must be some kind of the code.
我看你吸入的清洁剂太多了
You been spending too much time inhaling them cleaning products.
我警告你们 你们自己要注意
I'm warning you guys. You watch yourself.
他来这儿是有原因的 我想就是为了我们
This guy is here for a reason. And I think that reason is us.
让一让 老兄
Excuse me, buddy.
发生什么事了?
What's going on?
是纳沃斯基 他找到了新的岗位
It's Navorski. He's figured out the quarters.
下午好 欢迎光临汉堡王 您需要什么?
Good afternoon. Welcome to Burger King. May I take your order?
不用找了
Keep the change.
对不起
Excuse me.
好的 走开
OK, go. Go.
再见 谢谢
Good boy. Thank you.
再见
Bye-bye.
欢迎光临汉堡王 您需要
Welcome to Burger King. May I take your...
"危机 卡科日亚的危机"
"Crisis. Crisis in Krakozhia."
现在激烈的交火已经暂时结束
Now that heavy fighting has subsided
双方都在为冬天的持久战做准备
and both sides have dug in for the long winter ahead,
卡科日亚未来的局势短期内无法明朗
it's clear that the future of Krakozhia may be in doubt for some time to come.
同时 卡科日亚的人民却在饱受煎熬
Meanwhile, the people of Krakozhia suffer the consequences.
"食物 在 "
"And food... in..."
食物和能源短缺
... have caused food and energy shortages.
" 在卡科日亚"
"...in Krakozhia."
"百老汇的故事是 "
"The story of Broadway is the..."
情境喜剧"六人行"的角色背景
"The cast of comedy hit Friends
就设定在纽约市
which is set in New York.
朋友
Friends
因为暴风雪 所有航班都被取消
Due to the heavy snowfall, all flights have been cancelled...
"今天是韦恩·牛顿61岁生日"
"Wayne Newton is 61 today."
"真是奇迹"
"It's a miracle."
"韩国联体婴儿今天在缅因州 成功进行分离手术"
"Korean conjoined twins separated today in Maine."
"存活的几率是50%"
"Chances of survival 50-50."
50%
50-50.
下一位
Next.
我能问你些问题吗 纳沃斯基先生?
Let me ask you something, Mr Navorski.
我已经无能为力了 为什么你每天还在这里等着?
Why do you wait here every day when there's nothing I can do for you?
直到美国政府承认你的新国家 你才会有新的签证
Your new visa will not arrive until your country is recognized by the US.
你有两个章
You have two stamp.
一个红的 一个绿的
One red, one green.
-怎样?  -所有我有50%的机会进入纽约
-So?  -I have chance to go New York, 50-50.
是啊 你真是乐观 不过的美国的情况不是这样
Yes. That's a beautiful way to look at it, but America doesn't work that way.
作为地区委任专员 我要为肯尼迪机场新设置一个新岗位
As acting Field Commissioner, I've created a new position here at JFK.
旅客运输援助联络员
Transportation Liaison for Passenger Assistance.
头儿 他具体做什么呢?
Sir, what will that person do?
谢了 接下来交给我吧
Thank you. I'll take it from here.
我是运输联络员 负责援助旅客
I'm Transportation Liaison in charge of Passenger Assistance.
没有车 就没有硬币 没有硬币 就没有食物
No carts, no quarters. No quarters, no food.
不用多久他就会违反 第2章14条的规定走出那道大门
It'll be days before he goes through the doors in violation of section 2.14
那时候就是别人的问题了
Then he's somebody else's problem.
为什么我们现在不指控他违反了条例?
Why don't we tag him in violation of section 2.14 now?
然后拘留他
Then ship him to detention.
他只有离开才会犯法
He has to break the law by leaving.
老实说吧 特别是对付他这样的家伙
I won't lie, particularly to get rid of somebody like him.
-对不起 老兄  -亲爱的!
-Sorry, buddy.  -Honey!
放下 放下
Put it down. Put it down.
放下
Put it down.
你在用我的拖把 你在拖我的地板
You try to take my mop. You try to take my floor.
这是我的工作 离开我的地板 离我的拖把远点
It's my job. Stay off my floor. Stay away from my mop.
-食物  -如果你再碰它 我就杀了你
-Food.  -If you touch it again, I kill you.
嗨 我是恩里克·克鲁兹
Hey. I'm Enrique Cruz.
我要和你谈谈
We need to talk.
-我想和你做笔交易  -什么交易?
-I want to make a deal with you.  -What deal?
我想知道海关边境保护局 工作人员桃乐丝的一些信息
I need information on CBP Officer Torres.
你给我她的信息我就给你吃的
You feed me information about her and I'll feed you.
-你想知道什么?  -你每天就能见到她
-What do you want know?  -You see her every day.
我想知道什么使她双腿发软
I want to know what makes her knees weak.
让她热血沸腾 浑身兴奋
What makes her blood boil and her body tingle.
她是匹野母马 你要帮我征服她
She's a wild stallion and you'll help me break her.
我
I'm...
我是她命中注定的男人
I'm her man of mystery.
-桃乐丝是野的母马?  -她的名字是德洛丽丝
-Officer Torres is wild stallion?  -Her name is Delores.
你帮我赢得她的心 你就再也不会挨饿了
You help me to win her heart and you'll never go hungry again.
-成交  -真的?发誓?
-I do this.  -Really? Promise?
-是的  -好的 谢谢你
-Yes.  -OK. Thank you.
"野母马"是什么意思?
What mean, "wild stallion"?
桃乐丝小姐 我朋友说你是"种马"
Officer Torres. My friend say you are stallion.
纳沃斯基先生
Mr Navorski.
-是什么?  -种马 会跑的马
-A what?  -Stallion, like a horse.
站到黄线后面去
Stand behind the yellow line.
-是漂亮的马  -谁说的?
-It's beautiful horse.  -Who said that?
我的食物  我的朋友驾驶食物
My food! My friend drive the food.
纳沃斯基先生 站在黄线后面
Mr Navorski, behind the yellow line.
-现在还没有轮到你  -我去拿浅绿色表
-I will help once it's your turn.  -I'll get light green.
-浅绿色表  -我马上回来
-Light green form.  -I'll be back.
嗯
Mm.
她说了一件事
She say one thing.
-非常重要  -什么?她告诉你什么了?
-Very important.  -What? What did she tell you?
鱼肉有什么问题吗?
Something wrong with the salmon?
加点"结膜"
Need gorchitsa.
什么?
What?
芥末 芥末?
Mustard. Mustard?
-芥末?  -是的
-Mustard?  -Yes. Please.
谢谢
Thank you.
桃乐丝小姐 你喜欢看电影吗?
Officer Torres, you like the films?
-电影?  -不喜欢看
-Movies?  -Not so much.
-喜欢火箭  -买不起
-The Rockettes?  -Can't afford it.
-你喜欢什么?  -聚会
-What do you like?  -Conventions.
聚会是什么?
Conventions. What is?
-聚会  -聚会
-Conventions.  -Conventions?
就像你去的秘密基地什么的?
This is like secret place you go?
她穿成"星舰迷航记"里的约曼·兰德的样子去参加聚会
She go to these conventions dressed as Yeoman Rand.
-约曼·兰德  -她是星际迷航记迷
-Yeoman Rand.  -She's a Trekkie.
她最喜欢一集是"末日机器"
Favourite episode is Doomsday Machine.
现在 听着 维克多
Now, listen, Viktor.
你帮我问她一件非常重要的事情
You can ask her something that is very important.
-好的  -看
-OK.  -Look...
-我等着  -旅途愉快
-I wait.  -Enjoy your visit.
下一位
Next.
-桃乐丝小姐  -纳沃斯基先生
-Officer Torres.  -Mr Navorski.
让你选择
You have choose.
有钱的男人还是有爱的男人?
Man with money or man with love?
你选什么?
What is choose?
她有男朋友了?
She had a boyfriend?
多久了?二年了?
For how long? Two years?
到底发生什么了?
What happened?
他是"屎"
He chit.
-什么?  -他是"屎"
-What?  -He chit.
吃屎?
Eat shit?
他是"屎" 他是"屎" 他是"屎"
He chit. He chit. He chit.
-说得准确点  -他"屎" 被她发现了 所以
-Repeat exactly what she said.  -He chit. She catch him. So...
-他是骗子  -是的
-He cheats.  -Yes.
我们叫做"脚踩二条船"
What we call krushkach. We say krushkach.
一个男人 二个女人
One man, two womans.
所以
So. Mm.
太拥挤了 你知道吗
Crowded, you know.
好的 他是个骗子
OK. He cheats.
-你说"骗子"  -他是"屎"
-You say "cheats".  -He chit.
-是"骗子"  -对  对
No, "cheat".  -Enrique.
你不能"屎"她
You, no chit.
-不要欺骗她  -不要"屎"她
-No cheat.  -No chit.
不 我不会骗她
No. I won't cheat.
她是个好女孩 她不会上你的当
She's a nice girl. She won't take your chitting.
下一位
Next.
桃乐丝 你有没有恋爱过?
Officer Torres. Have you been ever in the love?
够了 维克多 到底是谁?
Enough, Viktor. Who is it?
是谁要你问我这些事情?
Who's telling you to ask me these things?
是个"悲惨"的男人
It's a man of misery.
悲惨?
Misery?
-神秘?  -不 不 "悲惨" "悲惨"的男人
-Mystery?  -No, no. Misery. Man of misery.
他已经爱的无法自拔
He's so sick. He's so in love.
不过她说了什么?
But what did she say?
她过去总是说 "下一位!下一位!"
She did say, "Next! Next!"
她现在说 "请 请过来"
And now she say, "Please. Please come."
是吗 等等
That's... Wait.
-我来了  -等一下 维克多
-I coming now.  -No, wait. Viktor.
维克多 再给我多讲点
Viktor, just tell me more.
我来了 我来了
I coming. I coming.
让一让
Please, please.
传呼机响了 所以 我拿着 我来了
Beeper went off. Started beeping. So, I grab. I come.
我们有个主意
We have an idea.
你需要些吃的吗?
Would you like something to eat?
不 不用 我吃饱了
No. No food. I stuffed.
好的
OK. All right.
谢谢
Thank you.
纳沃斯基先生 我有很好的消息要告诉你
So, Mr Navorski, I have some very good news for you.
什么?
What?
我找到了能让你离开机场的办法
I've figured out a way to get you out of this airport.
怎么办?
How?
我们有些保护外国人的法律
Well, we have laws here that protect aliens
保护那些惧怕返回自己国家的外国人
who have a credible fear of returning to their own country.
如果我们能确定你有这种恐惧
If we can establish this fear with you,
海关边境保护局必须使用转移程序
then the CBP will be forced to begin Expedited Removal Procedures,
把你的转移到移民法庭 为你的案子申请庇护
to bring you to an immigration judge and let you plead your case for asylum.
-庇护?  -对 庇护
-Asylum?  -Mm-hm, asylum.
不幸的是 法院这类案子已经堆积如山
Unfortunately, the courts are so backed up with asylum cases
最快也要六个月才能开庭
that the soonest you'd get before a judge would be six months from now.
是的 我们别无选择
Yes, and we would have no choice
只能让你这六个月获得自由 这是法律 你就自由了
but to let you go for those six months. It's the law. You'd be released.
你可以自由待在纽约等待开庭
You would be free to wait in New York until your court date.
不过 信不信由你 很多人再没有出现过
But, believe it or not, most people never show up before the judge.
我可以去纽约市了?
So I go New York City?
你今晚就可以进入纽约
You can go to New York City tonight.
不过我们必须确定你有"可靠的恐惧"
But, you only get to go if we can establish a credible fear.
-恐惧?  -恐惧
-Fear?  -Mm-hm, fear.
-恐惧  -恐惧
-Fear.  -Fear.
恐惧什么?
From what?
你问到点子上了
That's the best part.
你惧怕什么对"山姆大叔"并不重要
It doesn't matter what you're afraid of. It's all the same to Uncle Sam.
所以我要问你一个问题
So I'm going to ask you one question,
如果你能给我正确的答案 我今晚就能让你离开机场
if you give me the correct answer, I can get you out of this airport tonight.
我回答一个问题
So, I answer one question.
今晚就能进入纽约
Go to New York City. Tonight.
-今晚  -今晚
-Tonight.  -Tonight.
-好啊  -好啊
-OK.  -OK.
好的
All right.
你现在是否惧怕返回您的国家?
Do you, at this time, have any fear of returning to your own country?
不
No.
我们重新来一次
OK. Let me try it again.
-你的国家在打仗  -是的 战争
-Your country's at war.  -Yes. War.
街上到处都是拿着枪的男人 到处都是政治迫害
There are men in the streets with guns. Political persecution.
-是的 很可怕  -是啊 很恐怖
-Yes. It's terrible.  -Yeah, it's horrible.
天晓得以后会这么样
And God only knows what could happen.
无辜的人们背井离乡
Innocent people are torn from their beds.
在星期二 我讨厌星期二
On Tuesdays. I hate Tuesdays.
所以你害怕了
So you're afraid.
-害怕什么?
-From what?  -Krakozhia.
你害怕卡科日亚
You're afraid of Krakozhia.
卡科日亚?
Krakozhia?
不 我不害怕卡科日亚 我倒是有点怕这个房间
No, I am not afraid from Krakozhia. I'm a little afraid of this room.
我在说炸弹 我在说人的尊严
I'm talking about bombs. I'm talking about human dignity.
人权
Human rights.
维克多 告诉我你害怕卡科日亚 不用要担心什么
Viktor, please don't be afraid to tell me you're afraid of Krakozhia.
那是我家 我不害怕我的家
Is home. I am not afraid from my home.
我可以去纽约了吧?
So? I go to New York City now?
-不行  -不行?
-No.  -No?
好吧
OK.
-我害怕鬼  -非常感谢
-I'm afraid from ghosts.  -Thanks very much.
-我害怕吸血鬼  -多谢了
-I'm afraid from Dracula.  -Thanks a lot.
我害怕狼人 害怕鲨鱼
I'm afraid from Wolfmens, afraid from sharks.
非常感谢
Thanks a lot.
妈的
Damn.
-你为什么这么做?  -在美国没有人看指示牌
-Why you do this?  -Nobody read the sign in America.
这是我唯一有的乐趣
This is the only fun I have.
烧烤? 这就是你为什么不来看我?
A barbecue? That's why I'm not going to see you?
我跟你直说吧 为了见你 我改了所有的工作行程
Let me get this straight. I change my schedule to meet you.
我连飞了4个轮班
I take four back-to-back flights,
连续飞了27个小时 绕地球飞了几圈
fly 27 hours straight literally around the world,
现在你告诉我你要和 你妻子一起过国庆?
and now you tell me you're going to spend July 4th with your wife?
你妻子不喜欢看焰火
The woman hates fireworks.
不要骗我 好吗?
Don't lie to me, OK?
我知道上个周末你带她去罗马了
I know for a fact you took her to Rome last weekend.
因为你做的我们的飞机 麦克斯
Because you flew United, Max.
南美航空公司的 乘客沙里夫 卡拉尔
South African Airlines passenger Sharif Al-Calala,
请到总检票台来
please come to the main ticket counter.
你喜欢偷听别人谈话吗?
You make a habit out of listening to other people's conversations?
没有 我在打电话回家
No, I try to call home.
是吗
So then...
-你知道为什么男人都是混蛋吗?  -不知道
-You know why men are such assholes?  -No.
因为他们都是骗子
Because they're all liars.
等等 等等
Wait. Wait, wait, wait, wait.
地板湿滑
Wet floor.
小心受伤
Please. Don't be hurt.
我怎么会不受伤?他已经结婚了
How can I not be? He's married.
一个男人 二个女人 太麻烦了
One man. Two womens. Crowded.
你知道最坏的地方是什么吗?
You want to know what the worst part is?
我从来没有要他离开他的妻子 还鼓励他去和她沟通
I never asked him to leave his wife. I encouraged him to get counselling.
我是不是疯了?
What kind of sick person am I?
我竟然为他们着想
I'm rooting for the home team.
真希望和他做爱 不要这么迷人就好了
I just wish the sex wasn't so amazing.
-太迷人了  -再见
-So amazing.  -Bye-bye.
你知道吗 有时候早上起来
You know... sometimes in the mornings,
我这就这么痴痴的盯着他
I just stare at him over room service.
看他做拼字游戏
Watch him do the crossword puzzle.
我开始想也许 也许会真的发生
I start to think that maybe... maybe this could happen.
我们能够长相厮守
That we belong together.
这个 男人 有你
This... man... has you.
为什么他还 迷惑?
Why he need... puzzle?
这是我的问题
This is my problem.
我总是一厢情愿的看男人
I always see men the way I want to see them.
我们见过面吗?
Do I know you from someplace?
舒服的后跟 免费的鞋子 二楼
Sensible heels. Payless Shoes. Second floor.
你准备回家?
You headed for home?
不是 我
Er... No, no. I am...
我的班机已经延误很久了
I am delayed a long time.
我讨厌班机延误 你是做什么的?
I hate it when they delay flights. What do you do?
我从一栋建筑到另外一栋建筑
I go from one building to another building.
我有呼机
I have beeper.
建筑承包商 你们和我一样都经常在旅行
Oh, contractors. You guys travel as much as we do.
不要意思 非常感谢你
Sorry about that. Thank you very much.
什么是"BH"?
What's "BH"?
在英语里
In English...
维克多·纳沃斯基
Viktor Navorski.
-在英语里 阿米莉亚·沃伦
-In English, Amelia Warren.  -Amelia Warren?
-很高兴认识你  -我也是
-Nice to meet you.  -You, too.
下次再见
Nice to see you again.
你喜欢意大利菜吗?
You like Italian food?
我知道 很晚了 也许你有别的计划
I know, it's late and you've probably got other plans,
不过如果你想去吃点东西 我们可以马上搭车出去
but if you'd like to grab some dinner, we can run right out and catch a cab.
我知道有个餐馆的意大利肉卷很棒
I know a place that has the greatest cannelloni.
嗯
Erm...
不 我不能
No, I... I can't.
-你结婚了?  -没有
-You married?  -No.
-有女朋友?  -没有
-Girlfriend?  -No.
我 我不能和你 出去
I... I can't go out... with you.
天啊 真是对不起
God. I am so... I'm so sorry.
非常对不起
I am so sorry.
我真的是被我的工作和生活搞疯了
I must come off like a complete nut job or something.
-没有  -我不想一个人吃饭
-No.  -I didn't want to eat alone.
湿地板 湿地板
Wet floor. Wet floor.
-我  -你不用解释
-I...  -You don't have to explain.
不是 我 请 我
No, I... Please, I...
不是 我
No, I...
请送轮椅到A5号门
Wheelchair to gate A-five.
娜蒂亚
Nadia.
纽约餐馆里意大利肉卷要多少钱?
In New York restaurant, what cost is cantaloni?
不知道 大概15元
I don't know. Maybe 15 bucks.
-美元?  -20
-Dollars?  -20.
二个人 40
Two people, 40.
二个人 40美元
Two people, 40 dollars.
我 我 帮你?
I... I... help you?
对不起 先生 我们已经招满人了
I'm so sorry, sir. The position has already been filled.
-你住在附近吗?  -是的 67号门
-Do you live nearby?  -Yes. Gate 67.
因为我们需要非常守时 你说67号门?
Because we are very particular about punctual... Did you say Gate 67?
67号门
Gate 67.
你一定是开玩笑
You got to be kidding.
你要让我帮你 不过你没有社保号码
You got to help me help you. I don't see a Social Security number...
通讯地址 连电话号码也没有
...mailing address, even a phone number.
电话?你需要吗?我有 我有电话
Telephone? You need? I get. I get. I get phone.
我有 我有电话
I get... I get phone.
451-1226
451-1226.
好的 最好什么时候打给你
All right. When's the best time to reach you?
现在?
Now?
-你好?  -嗨 纳沃斯基先生
-Hello?  -Hi, Mr Navorski.
是的 我是维克多 纳沃斯基 你是那位?
Yes, this is Viktor Navorski. Who calls?
我是探索专卖店的克利夫
It's Cliff from the Discovery Store.
克利夫 你好
Cliff. Hello.
-还好吧?  -很好
-How's it going?  -Good.
-现在打电话合适吗?  -是的 我等你电话一天了
-Is this a good time?  -Yes, I wait for your call all day.
我要告诉你这个职位已经有人了
Well, I got to tell you that the position's been filled.
所以你能不能坐到其他地方去
Yeah, so could you please go sit someplace else?
-我到洗手间去  -非常感谢
-I go to bathroom now.  -That'd be good.
-好的  -谢谢
-All right.  -Thank you.
好的
OK.
他是谁?
Who is this?
-你是谁?  -不知道
-Who are you?  -It's no one.
这里二个星期都没人 不是我的人
There's no one here for two weeks. This isn't one of my guys.
看看这墙壁 不错的手艺
Look at this cornicing. This is good work.
一定是哈利的人 你是哈利的人吗?
Must be Harry's crew. You with Harry's crew?
哈利知道他在这里工作吗?
Does Harry think he's running this job?
-我走了  -走?走到那去?
-I go now.  -Go? Go where?
-67号门  -67?
-Gate 67.  -67?
67号门的工程还早着呢
We're ten months away from 67.
他既不是你的人也不是我的 一定是哈利的人
He's got to be Harry's. If he's not mine and he's not yours...
哈利是想让我难看啊
Harry's trying to make me look bad.
我才不会让他就这么 得到67号门的工程
I've got to slow him down before he gets to 67.
-你叫什么名字?  -纳沃斯基
-What's your name?  -Viktor Navorski.
把他从哈利的队伍挖出来 我需要他
Pull him off Harry's crew, put him on mine.
明天早上6:30上班
You start 6.30 Monday morning.
你给我工作?
You give me job?
6:30 好的 老板
6.30, yes... Boss.
今天午夜 不要迟到
jazz plays on personal stereo
有意大利航空公司的龙虾饺
We have lobster ravioli from Alitalia.
俄国航空总局的鱼子酱
We have caviar from Russian Aeroflot.
好的 拿过来
OK. Just bring it.
-嗨 维克多  -你们好
-Hey, Viktor.  -Hello, all.
看啊 没有国家的男人
Look. The man without a country.
过来 欢迎
Come on in. Welcome.
-我看到这个了  -做的不错
-I see this.  -You did well.
请坐
Have a seat.
-这里?  -这里
-Here?  -Here.
来吧 坐下
Come on, sit down.
-谁邀请他的?  -是我 我们三缺一 不是吗?
-Who invited him?  -I did. We needed a fourth, right?
-我不想和他一起玩  -古普塔 别紧张好吗?
-I'm not going to play with him.  -Gupta, relax, would you?
-他不是间谍  -你怎么知道?
-He isn't a spy.  -How do you know?
他会记录下我们的谈话 他的衬衣里有窃听器
He could be recording everything we say. A wire in his shirt.
他的头发里有麦克风
A microphone up in his ass.
-我可不想被炒鱿鱼  -好的
-I'm not going to lose my job.  -Fine.
-我们给他照个x光好吧?  -好的
-What if we x-rayed him?  -Yes.
闭上你的眼睛
Close your eyes.
-好了 你是清白的  -好的 我们玩牌吧
-OK. So you are clean.  -Good. Let's play cards.
我有钱 不过要到星期五
I will have money. But... Friday.
不要担心 我们用机场遗失物品做赌注
Don't worry about it. We play for unclaimed items from the Lost and Found.
你绝对想不到人们会在 机场留下些什么 来吧
You'll be amazed at what people leave at airports. Come.
我有二对九和二对九
I have two nines and two nines.
四个九 谢了
Four nines. Thank you.
-小心  -注意
-Careful.  -Watch out.
-我们有问题想问你  -我们很好奇
-We have a question for you.  -Yeah, we're just curious.
罐子里面是什么?
What is in the can?
-这个?  -我们在X光里看到的
-This?  -We saw the x-ray.
我们知道里面没有吃的了
We know there's no nuts in there.
这里面有什么?
What is in there?
这是爵士乐
This is jazz.
-爵士乐?  -是的 爵士乐
-Jazz?  -Jazz, yes.
-爵士乐?  -是的
-Jazz?  -Yes.
你肯定里面是爵士乐吗? 可能还是蓝调的
You sure it's jazz in there? It might be the blues.
-或者拉丁风格  -也许是史提夫·汪德
-Or salsa.  -Maybe it's Stevie Wonder.
-不 不 是爵士乐  -好的 好
-No, no, is jazz.  -OK, guys. OK.
今晚的最丰盛的奖品就是
For tonight's grand prize, we have...
给他们看看 古普塔
Show them, Gupta.
我在楼上找到了这个
I found this upstairs.
澳大利亚航空公司 头等舱
Virgin Air, first class lounge.
来了
There you go.
是谁的?
And... they belong to?
谢尔
Cher.
谢尔?
Cher?
是谢尔的?
As in... Cher?
是的 谢尔
Yeah. Cher.
我调查过了 有目击者的
I checked it out. There were witnesses.
是谢尔的内裤
Those are Cher's panties.
-准备好了吗?  -快点
-Ready?  -Hurry up.
我们会分享这条内裤?
So, will we share the panties?
-不 不  -它是我的
-No, no, no.  -Not if I win.
-来吧  -等等
-Come on.  -Wait a second.
联合航空公司飞往 成田机场的801航班
United Airlines flight number 801 to Narita
马上就要起飞了
is now announcing final boarding.
"不行" "这是我的"
"You can't. That is mine."
"你会很烦恼的"
"You can get so confused."
维克多?
Viktor?
嗨
Well, hi.
请让我来
Please.
-最近怎么样?  -很好
-How are you?  -Good.
伙计
Man.
上次那样约你出去 我真的很抱歉
I am so sorry about what happened last time, asking you out like that.
所有男人就算在3000尺的高空 都会设法摸我的屁股
I'm so used to guys trying to grab my ass at 30,000 feet
当我真正遇到一个没这种想法的人时
that when I meet somebody that doesn't
我却不知道该如何面对了
I don't know how to react.
-让我们先不聊这个了  -好的
-Let's just start over.  -Yes, OK.
-你是离开还是回来?  -我也不知道 都是吧
-Are you coming or going?  -I don't know. Both.
那是什么意思 和我说说吧
Tell me about it.
拿破仑?
Napoleon?
是啊 我读过很多历史小说
Yeah. I read a lot of history books.
都是价廉物美的书 不过内容都是杀来杀去
They're long and cheap.
像这1200页只要9.99美元 这个价钱太诱惑人了
Like 1200 pages for $9.99. You can't beat that.
-但是这个 拿破仑?  -是啊 关于他的书是我的最爱
-But Napoleon?  -Yeah. He's one of my favourites.
-你知道是什么拯救了拿破仑的命吗?  -不知道
-You know what saved Napoleon's life?  -No.
-他的自负  -自负?
-His ego.  -Ego?
是的
Yes.
在他经历了滑铁卢惨败之后
After he loses the Battle of Waterloo,
拿破仑把自己单独留在一个小小的圣海伦娜岛上
Napoleon isolates himself on the tiny island of Saint Helena.
确切的来说没有人知道后来发生了什么
No one knows exactly what happens next,
不过我比较喜欢的一个版本是这样说的
but the version I like goes like this:
他十分沮丧 并且准备结束自己的生命
He's very depressed and decides to take his own life.
但是拿破仑相信他自己 具有超于常人的体质
But Napoleon believes himself to be of such superhuman strength
所以他服用了6倍于常人剂量的毒药
that he takes six times the amount of poison needed to do the job.
他的胃里塞满了毒药 他的身体产生排斥作用
His stomach is so full up with poison that his body rejects it,
他于是死里逃生
and he doesn't die.
明白吗? 自负 救了他的命
See? Ego. Saved his life.
或许他需要一副眼镜
Maybe he need glasses.
-眼镜?  -是的 这样就可以看清药瓶上写的字
-Glasses?  -Yes. To read words on bottle.
毒药
Poison.
你这个说法真的很有趣
It's funny you should say that.
有谣传说拿破仑的确是远视眼
Rumour has it that Napoleon was farsighted.
-你说得不错  -说得不错?
-There you go.  -There you go.
-说得不错  -你说得不错
-There you go.  -And there you go.
维克多我认为我们正在这里改写历史
I think we're rewriting history right here.
为什么我们不边吃午餐边谈这个?
Why don't we talk about it over lunch?
上帝 不敢相信我又这样随便约你了
Oh, my God, I can't believe it. I just asked you out again.
我又这样做了
I just did it again.
看来我 最好离我远点 维克多 好吗?
I'm so... Just stay away from me, Viktor, OK?
我有病 我简直无法 单独活着超过5秒钟
I'm sick. I don't have the ability to be alone for five seconds.
好的
OK.
-什么好的?  -好的
-OK, what?  -OK.
和你共进午餐
Lunch... with you.
-你会和我一起吃午餐?  -是的
-You'll have lunch with me?  -Yes.
你不用搭飞机吗?或者...
You're not running for a flight or...?
我可以等
I wait.
-是我的  -你的? 是的
-It's me.  -You. Yes.
我很抱歉 我刚刚收到信息
I'm sorry. I just got paged.
你要去工作?
You work?
不是的
-No.  -Ah.
就是你们3个人 互相挤在一起?
Three of you. Crowded.
最好离我远点 维克多
Stay away from me, Viktor.
我 我有个很严重的问题 我和拿破仑一样不太健康
I'm... I have a serious problem. I'm as bad as Napoleon.
我不停的在吸取那些"有毒"的男人 直到让我自己不可救药
I just keep ingesting these poisonous men until I make myself sick.
-你没病 阿米莉亚 没有  -没有?
-You're not sick, Amelia. No.  -No?
没有 你只是有点"远视"而已
No. You're a little... farsighted.
-我得走了  -我得留下
-I have to go.  -I have to stay.
-这就是我的生活  -我也一样
-Story of my life.  -Me, too.
边境保护局视察员 将在3天以内到达
Your CBP inspection's in three days.
FBI和国家安全局将会巡视机场
The FBI and Homeland Security will tour the airport,
在和你谈话以前 他们将花2小时视察这些办公室
spend two hours observing these offices before your interview process begins.
纳沃斯基到底挣多少?
How much does Navorski make?
先生?
Sir?
他到底挣多少? 他们到底付多少钱给他?
How much does he make? How much are they paying him?
他们偷偷地付给他现金
They're paying him cash under the table.
这我知道 到底有多少?
I know that. How much?
每小时19美元
$19 an hour.
难以置信 你知道吗 他比我挣的还要多
Unbelievable. Do you know that's more than I make?
那就是纽约城市建设公司的薪酬
That's New York City construction.
几天前 我的一个手下来找我
One of my own men came up to me the other day.
问我要不要也去赌一把
Asked me if I wanted to join the big pool.
你看看他
Look at him.
赌在什么时候纳沃斯基会离开这个机场
Place a bet on when Navorski's going to leave this airport.
你听说了这事没有?
Have you heard about this?
我赌他留到一月三日
I have January 3rd.
把他带进来
Bring him in.
杰克 他没有国籍 懂吗? 没有国家
Jake, he has no nationality. OK? No country.
从我们章程的第2章12节的解释 他对国家是个安全隐患
He's a national security risk, according to my interpretation of Section 2.12.
我想要你把他关进拘留中心 对他进行一次全面审察
I want you to put him in a detention centre and run a clearance on him.
我只要这样就够了
That's all I want.
那么联邦监狱可以吗?
What about a federal prison?
要么另外一个机场也行?
What about another airport?
喂? 喂?
Hello? Hello?
我们已经拘留了太多的人 到处都是人满为患
We're detaining so many people, there's no room anywhere.
-你试过联系FBI了吗?  -谁我都试了 没人想要接手他
-Did you try the FBI?  -I tried everybody. Nobody'll take him.
你想要我把他带回候机室吗?
You want me to bring him back to the terminal?
不用了 从现在起 纳沃斯基就住在这里
No. From now on, Navorski lives here.
今天来这里的这些人 是来观察我 审查我的
The people who are coming here today will be observing me, inspecting me.
但是他们大部分人都会 留心这个机场各个运行环节
But most of all they will be looking at the way that this airport is run.
所以 让我们展示给他们 什么是全美第一的机场
So let's show them why this is the number-one airport in the United States.
我们每天大约要处理600次航班
We process about 600 planes a day,
平均每37分钟一班飞机
with a processing time of 37 minutes per plane,
每60秒运送一位乘客
about 60 seconds per passenger...
进入这个国家
...to be brought into the country.
我们尽力保证完善的检查
We keep it as clean as possible.
-你带什么入关?  -电脑软件
-What do you import?  -Computer software.
真是很多胡桃啊
That's a lot of walnuts.
是啊 我的岳母十分 喜欢这些东西
Yeah. My mother-in-law loves these things.
每次我去巴西以后 都要给她带一袋回来
Every time I go to Brazil, I bring her back a bag.
-你的岳母?  -是啊
-Your mother-in-law?  -Yeah.
介意我尝一个吗?
Mind if I try one?
你是怎么知道这些东西 不是给他岳母带的?
How did you know those weren't for his mother-in-law?
如果他结了婚的话 为什么他没戴结婚戒指?
If he's married, where's his ring?
如果他是离了婚的人 谁还会理会他的岳母呢?
And if he's divorced, who still talks to their mother-in-law?
很抱歉 但是真的 我无意冒犯别人的岳母 不过
I'm sorry, but really. No offence to mother-in-laws, but...
-长官  -是的
-Sir.  -Yeah.
长官 楼上出状况了
Sir, we have a situation upstairs.
-等下再说吧  -不行 这件事可等不起
-It'll have to wait.  -No. This won't wait.
从多伦多来的912航班降落后
When the 9.12 from Toronto landed
他们发现了4瓶没有检验过的药物
They found four prescriptions without an MPL.
他们准备把这些药扣留 这个人就发了狂
They tried to take the pills away and he went nuts.
这就是他了 我们猜测这些药物是给他父亲的
There he is. We think they're for his father.
先生 先生 冷静下来 放下你的武器
Sir, sir, calm down. Put your weapons down.
大家收好自己的武器 好的 我们是来帮助你的
Everybody keep your weapons... All right. We're here to help you.
我们是来帮助你的 先生 好了 把刀给我吧
We're here to help you, sir. All right. Give me the knife.
-他从哪来的?  -俄罗斯
-Where's he from?  -Russia.
我们唯一的翻译 现在人在纽华克
The only interpreter we got is in Newark.
-我们最好找个人和他谈谈  -我有个主意 长官
-We have to get someone to talk to him.  -I have an idea, sir.
维克多
Viktor.
-Viktor.
喔
Oh...
我需要你帮忙
I need your help.
他的名字是米洛卓戈维奇 他住的地方离你家很近
His name is Milodragovich. He lives near you.
他可能不会说你们那里的方言
He may not speak your dialect,
但是我确实需要你帮我渡过难关
but I need you to translate and help me out.
-我帮你? 为什么?  -因为我不想有任何人受伤
-I help you? Why?  -I don't want anybody to get hurt.
这家伙现在十分生气
This guy's very upset.
让他冷静下来 我就让你回候机大厅去
Just calm him down and I'll let you back in the terminal.
不行 我要去纽约 不要再盖 红色的章 要绿的 我要盖绿色的
No. New York. No red stamp. Green. I green.
-纽约  -好的 可以
-New York.  -OK, yes.
-你说好的?  -是的
-You say yes?  -Yes.
-好的 好的 好的 好的  -离我远点!
-OK. OK, OK, OK.  -Stay out!
我们有个人想和你谈谈 和你谈谈 去吧
We have somebody here to talk to you. Somebody to talk to you. Go ahead.
离我远点!
Stay out!
怎么样?
So?
好的 告诉他要从本国携带药物出境
OK, tell him in order to export medicines from this country,
他必须要持有购药许可证
he needs to have the proper form, a Medicinal Purchase Licence.
你明白我的意思吗 维克多?
OK? You understand me, Viktor?
他说这些药是为他父亲买的
He say he bring the medicine for his father.
所以他才去加拿大为他父亲买药
This why he go to Canada. Medicine for father.
那不重要
It doesn't matter.
他的班机降落在了美国 他就必须持有许可证
His plane landed in the US. He needs to have the right form.
他不知道需要这种文件
He did not know he need this document.
没有人告诉他需要什么文书
No one say to him he need document form.
我不是在告诉他吗
I'm saying it to him.
他需要当地给他父亲进行治疗的医院所签署的申请表
He needs to have the form signed by the hospital who is treating his father.
这些药物必须留在美国
These medicines have to stay in the United States.
它们必须扣留在这里
They have to stay here.
他 他在求你
He... He's begging you.
我知道 我看得出他在求我
I know. I can see that he's begging.
先生 我很抱歉
I'm sorry, sir.
你必须搭乘早上的班机离开 药得留在这里
You'll have to take a flight in the morning. The medicine stays here.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
压住他!
Send him down!
多谢你 维克多 干得不错 我们走吧
Thank you, Viktor. Good job. Let's go.
山羊
Goat.
-什么?  -山羊 这些是给山羊用的药
-What?  -Goat. It medicine is for goat.
-山羊?  -是的 药是给山羊用的 山羊
-Goat?  -Yes. Medicine is for goat. Goat.
-是他说得?  -是的
-He said that?  -Yes.
他说
He say...
我们没听懂 是我没听懂 "山羊"
We not understand. I not understand "goat".
为什么? 你在说什么? 你没听懂他的话?
Why? What are you saying? You misunderstood him?
-不是买给他垂危的父亲吗?  -不 不是的
-It's not for his dying father?  -No. No.
在 卡科日亚文里 "父亲"这个词
The... Krakozhia... The name for "father"...
念起来有点像 "山羊"
sound like "goat".
是我弄错了
I make mistake.
你为什么要这样做 维克多?
Why are you doing this, Viktor?
药物是给 山羊用的
Medicine is for... goat.
-不 不是的  -是的
-No, it's not.  -Yes.
-不是的  -是的
-No.  -Yes.
你看过了蓝色移民表
You read the blue immigration form.
-蓝色那张?  -是的 蓝色的
-Blue?  -Yes. Blue.
-蓝色?  -蓝色 蓝色的表格
-Blue?  -Blue. The blue form.
那上面说:如果药物是给动物用的话 就不需要许可证了
The one that says if it's an animal, he doesn't need the licence.
那他就可以把药带进来了 真是不错 维克多 真的不错
Then he can bring the drugs in. That's good, Viktor. That's very good.
你为什么要这样做? 嗯?
Why are you doing this? Huh?
你根本不认识他 你也不知道规矩
You don't know him. You don't know the rules.
看着我
Look at me.
我是想要帮你
I was going to help you.
现在我想要你问他 不 不是你说
Now I want you to ask him... No, not you.
我想要你问他 我要听到他的回答
I want you to ask him. I want to hear him say it.
我要听他亲口说 这些药到底是给谁的
I want to hear him say who the medicine is for.
请说 这些药到底是给谁用的?
Please. Who the medicine is for.
回答他 米洛卓戈维奇先生 这些药到底是给谁用的?
Answer him, Mr Milodragovich. Who are the pills for?
好了 药留下 把他送走 就这样
OK. The pills stay. He goes. That's it.
山羊
Goat.
给山羊的
Please. For goat.
给山羊的药
Medicine for goat.
把药给他
Give him the pills.
给山羊的药
Medicine for goat.
药
Medicine...
过来把 结束了
Come on now, it's all over.
他很爱他的山羊
He love that goat.
你认为我需要什么借口 才能把你丢回牢房去吗
Do you think I need an excuse to put you back in that cell
把你关上5年?
to keep you there for five years?
你和我作对就是和美国为敌
You go to war with me, and you go to war with the United States.
那样你就会知道当卡科日亚人民排队买草纸的时候
Then you'll know why Krakozhians wait in line for cheap toilet paper
美国人就已经用名牌双层厕纸来擦屁股了
while Uncle Sam wipes his ass with Charmin two-ply.
那里当时有20个人
There was a 20 man.
移民局的警卫们都拔枪了
Immigration gun was drawn.
狄克逊已经准备要开枪了
The Dixon was ready to fire.
杀掉那个拿着药片的可怜人
To kill the little man with the pills.
但是这时候有个人走进了房间 站到了这个可怜人的前面
But then someone walks into the room and stand in front of this little man.
"把枪放下 " 他这样说
"Put the guns away," the man say.
"今天没有人会死 "
"Nobody will die today."
是谁?
Who?
-是谁救了他?  -是啊 告诉我们 到底是谁?
-Who was it that saved him?  -Yeah, tell us. Who was it?
这个人是谁?
Who was this man?
纳沃斯基 维克多 "山羊" 纳沃斯基
Navorski. Viktor "The Goat" Navorski.
-做的不漂亮啊 弗兰克  -我只是按规矩办事罢了
-It doesn't look good, Frank.  -I was just following the rules.
有时候你必须把规矩放到一边 人才是最重要的
Sometimes you have to ignore the rules and concentrate on the people.
人 我了解
The people, I know.
对人 要有同情之心 这是国家建立的根基
The people, compassion. That's the foundation of this country.
你应该可以从纳沃斯基身上学到些什么
You could learn something from Navorski.
振奋点 事情还没完呢
Cheer up. It's not over yet.
-那是给我的吗?  -是的 是的
-Is that for me?  -Yes. Yes.
维京岛的旗鱼
Is Virgin Isle swordfish.
给你的
For you.
给"墙"的
For wall.
鱼是用来挂墙上的
Fish for wall.
你为什么想要去纽约?
Why do you want to go to New York?
还有那罐头里到底是什么?
And what's in the can of peanuts?
承诺
Promise.
-罐子里装着承诺?  -是的 一个承诺
-A promise in the can?  -Yes. A promise.
那么让我给你一个承诺吧 维克多
Let me make you a promise, Viktor.
一个被困在这个部门的人的承诺
And this is a promise that comes from a man who is stuck here.
一个可能还要在这里继续困上十年的人的承诺
A man who may be stuck here for the next ten years.
从现在起 你就是我的搭档了
From now on, you and I are partners.
只要我留在这里 你也留在这里
If I stay, you stay.
你一步也不能踏上纽约的土地
You will not set one foot in New York City.
一个脚趾头也不能碰到美利坚合众国的土地
Not a single toe in the United States of America.
你懂我在和你说什么吗?
Do you understand what I am saying to you?
是的
Yes.
你不喜欢鱼
You don't like fish.
你是不是有时候觉得自己就像住在机场里一样?
Do you ever feel like you're just living in an airport?
我们不需要这样做 维克多 我可以把你装在箱子里运出去
We don't have to do this, Viktor. I can ship you out in a crate.
我可以把你寄到美国的任何一个地方
I can mail you anywhere in the US.
我送食物的小车怎么样? 他可以躲在里面 我再把他带出去
What about my food cart? He can hide inside and we'll drive out.
-不行 我不能这样做  -你说过想要我们帮你
-No. I can't do this.  -You said you wanted us to help you.
-我是这样说了  -她叫什么?
-I do.  -What's her name?
阿米莉亚 沃伦
Amelia Warren.
我觉得我们应该向外走吧 怎么现在是向里走?
I thought we were looking for a way out, not a way in.
小心点 这些空姐可不是一般的女人
Be careful. Those flight attendants ain't like regular women.
总是在不同时区飞来飞去 扰乱了她们的生物钟
Flying back and forth between time zones messes with their biological clock.
-她们时刻准备着和你做爱  -好了 我找到些东西
-They're always ready for sex.  -OK, I found something.
我要走了 他们会来抓我们的
I am leaving. They will come for us.
古普塔 你不能放松一点吗? 只要看好你的门
Gupta, will you relax? Just watch the door.
你们会坐牢的 我可不想
You go in jail. Not me.
为 你知道为什么? 算了
For... You know what? Forget it.
-继续找  -沃伦 是吗?
-Keep looking.  -Warren, right?
-是的 是的  -沃伦
-Yes. Yes.  -Warren.
阿米莉亚 简 沃伦?
Amelia Jane Warren?
-简?  -是的
-Jane?  -Yeah.
找到了 维克多 在头等舱
Way to go, Viktor. First class.
-她什么时候回来?  -3周以后
-When she come back?  -Three weeks.
阿米莉亚 想一起去随便吃点什么吗?
Amelia, would you like to get eat to bite?
随便吃点什么? 意大利肉卷?
Bite to eat? Cantaloni?
随便吃点什么?
Bite to eat?
吃点随便什么? 吃点随便什么
Eat to bite? Eat to bite.
随便吃点什么
Bite to eat.
随便吃点什么 随便吃点什么
Bite to eat. Bite to eat.
随便吃点什么 随便吃点什么 随便吃点什么
Bite to eat. Bite to eat. Bite to eat.
随便吃点什么 随便吃点什么 随便吃点什么...
Bite to eat. Bite to eat. Bite to eat...
古普塔 你结过婚吗?
Gupta, you been ever married?
-你说什么?  -你结过婚吗?
-What did you say?  -You been ever married?
在印度我有一个老婆和二个孩子 23年前我离开了他们
I had a wife and two kids in India. I left them there 23 years ago.
为什么?
Why?
我在马德拉斯市有一家烟草店
I had a small tobacco shop in Madras.
挣得钱仅仅能维持生计
Made just enough money to survive.
一天 有一个警察来找我 说我欠他一些保护费
One day this policeman comes in and tells me I owe him some tax.
我说没问题 这很正常 所以我给了他
I said OK. This is common. So I pay him.
第二天 第三天 又是这个警察继续来问我收保护费
The next day, the same policeman come and keep coming and keep coming.
我也一次又一次的付给他
And I am paying and I'm paying him and I'm paying him and I'm paying him.
最后 第五天的时候 我拿起一把小刀刺进了他的胸口
And finally, on the fifth day, I take a knife and I stab him in his chest.
-你杀了个警察?  -没有 我没刺中他的心脏
-You killed policeman?  -No. I just missed his heart.
当他们来逮捕我的时候 我跑路了
When they tried to arrest me, I run away.
那么你再没有回过家?
So you never go home?
如果我回去的话 我要蹲七年的大牢
If I go home, I go in the jail for seven years.
要是美国政府抓住了你 他们把你遣送回国呢
What if United States catch you? They deport you.
只要我能够把地板扫干净 低调的做人
As long as I keep my floor clean, keep my head down,
他们就没什么理由驱逐我出去
they have no reason to deport me.
他们也没必要注意我这样的人啊
They have no reason to notice a man like me.
美国航空公司从罗马来的2703航班 已经抵达C43号门
United Airlines Flight 2703 from Rome is now arriving at Gate C43.
-嗨 等一下  -对不起 很抱歉
-Hey, wait.  -Sorry. I'm sorry.
不行 不 不 地板是湿的
No, no, no. It's wet.
走路小心点
-Hey.  -Watch where you're going.
当心点!
Watch out!
-阿米莉亚  -维克多
-Amelia.  -Viktor.
-你好  -对不起 我很抱歉
-Hello.  -Sorry. I'm sorry.
他差点杀了我
He nearly killed me.
-你没事吧?  -我很好
-You OK?  -I'm fine.
这套西装很不错呀
I love the suit.
名牌服装
Hugo Boss.
仅售149.99美元
On sale, $149.99.
真便宜啊
That's a bargain.
-拿破仑?  -是的 是的
-Napoleon?  -Yes, yes.
和约瑟芬
And Josephine.
你知道拿破仑和约瑟芬结婚的那天 送了她什么礼物吗?
Do you know what Napoleon gave Josephine on their wedding day?
阿米莉亚?
Amelia?
你愿不愿意一起去 随便吃点什么?
Would you like to have eat to bite?
吃饭 今晚?
Food. Tonight?
-你约我一起吃晚餐?  -是的
-You're asking me out for dinner?  -Yes.
可以 当然
Yeah. Sure.
-那什么时候?  -晚饭的时候
-What time?  -Dinnertime.
-你想去什么饭店?  -我知道一个不错的地方
-Where do you want to go?  -I know place.
-你有预约吗?  -纳沃斯基
-Do you have an appointment?  -Navorski.
这边请
This way, please.
谢谢
Thank you.
我不知道这里还有个院子
I didn't know they had a patio up here.
看起来很不错
It's very nice.
晚安
Good night.
当心 当心 当心
Please. Please. Please. Please.
对不起 今晚我们提供意大利肉卷和鸡肉
Sorry. So, tonight we have cannellonis or chicken.
-请来意大利肉卷  -意大利肉卷
-Cannelloni, please.  -Cannelloni.
-对不起  -谢谢
-Sorry.  -Thank you.
你要什么 先生?
For you, sir?
-一样  -那真的很好 很好的选择
-Same.  -That's a great, great choice.
我马上回来
I'll be back.
让我看看 请慢用
Let me see. Enjoy.
你知道这种羊角面包是罗马尼亚人发明的吗?
Did you know the croissant was invented in Romania?
-和我说说  -好的
-Tell me.  -OK.
1742年土耳其人入侵了布加勒斯特
It's 1742 and the Turks invade Bucharest,
他们借着月色进行了一次奇袭
making a surprise attack under the cover of night.
但是当地的面包师父...
But the town bakers...
对不起
Sorry.
那么 那位面包师父怎么了?
So, the bakers?
-算了 别介意 这是个很傻的故事  -继续把 求你了
-No, never mind. It's a dumb story.  -No, please.
我很抱歉 维克多
I'm sorry, Viktor.
没人会在乎羊角面包是怎么发明的
Nobody really cares where the croissant was invented.
我打赌就连那些罗马尼亚人都不会在意这事
I'll bet the Romanians themselves don't give a shit.
我在意
I care.
这是历史啊 是事实
Is histories. Is truth.
-我已经39岁了  -不会把
-I'm 39 years old.  -No.
-是的  -不会把
-Yeah.  -No.
-这是个事实  -你一定不是
-That's the truth.  -You are not.
我告诉别人我33岁 我约会的男人都觉得我只有27 但不是
I tell everybody I'm 33, and most of the men I've dated think I'm 27, but no.
我已经39了
I'm 39.
那又怎么样? 我也曾经39岁过
So? I was 39 once.
当我只有18岁时 我就开始为航空公司工作
I was 18 years old when I started working for the airlines.
我已经干这行有20多年了
I've been doing this over 20 years.
现在这一切都不需要再掩饰了
And now there's no more pretending.
这就是我
This is it.
所以我的地址簿是按城市划分的
It's why my address book is by city…
我的传呼机总是在吃饭的时候响起
…and my pager goes off during dinner.
你可以关掉你的传呼机
You can switch off pager.
我希望我能
I wish I could.
整整7年了 我一直在等一个电话
I've been waiting for a phone call for seven years.
我知道它会来的 维克多
I know it's coming, Viktor.
这就是我为什么不愿意关掉它的原因
That's why I can't break it off.
这就是为什么我总是住在旅馆里 时时刻刻准备好我的手提箱
That's why I live out of hotels and have my little suitcase packed, ready to go,
如果他想要和我共度周末的话 我能够随时出发
just in case he wants to meet me for the weekend.
是啊
Yeah.
我这一辈子都在等待着
I've been waiting my whole life.
只是不知道到底在等谁
-Just don't know what the hell for.  -[Pager vibrates]
我真的很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
我住在这里
I live here.
-什么?  -我住在这里 就在候机室
-What?  -I live here, in terminal.
67号门
Gate 67.
-你住在机场里  -是的 日日夜夜
-You live at the airport?  -Yes. Day and night.
这里是家 和你一样 他们叫我等待
This home, like you. They tell me to wait.
所以我等着
So I wait.
所有经常飞来飞去的人 都和你有同样的感觉 维克多
All frequent fliers feel the same way you do, Viktor.
所有的人都在等待 所有的人
Everybody's waiting. Everybody.
-等着航班 等着开会  -我不是在等航班或者会议
-For a flight, for a meeting...  -I don't wait for flight or meeting.
那么你在等什么?
Then what are you waiting for?
没关系 我了解
Is OK. I understand.
我有个主意了
I have an idea.
-过来  -你干什么?
-Come here.  -What you do?
你确定吗?
You sure?
比任何时候都确定
More than anything, I'm sure of this.
准备好了吗?
Ready?
那么 你什么时候回来?
So, when do you come back?
13天后 你呢?
13 days. How about you?
我会在这里
I will be here.
要是你改变了计划怎么办?
But what if your schedule changes?
或许我们应该交换一下电话号码
Maybe we should exchange phone numbers.
不必了 我会在这里的
No. I will be here.
你知道拿破仑征服巴伐利亚后 给了约瑟芬什么礼物吗?
You know what Napoleon give to Josephine when he win Bavaria?
告诉我把
Tell me.
别这样 告诉我把
Come on. Tell me.
我会给你看的 13天以后
I will show you. 13 days from now.
他在干吗?
What's he doing?
我不能问他 我应该是指挥他干什么的人
I can't ask him. I'm supposed to tell him what he's doing.
如果我反过来问他 会让我像个白痴一样
If I ask him, I look like an idiot.
我很抱歉 对不起了 你得要帮我这个忙
I'm sorry. Sorry. You got to do this for me.
事成之后 我保证让你吃的肠肥脑满
You'll get really fat with all the food I'm going to give you.
但是 求求你了 这是我最后一次求你为我做事了
But, please, do this for me. It will be the last thing I ask you to do.
他会在餐厅等你的回复
He waits for you to answer at Sbarro.
-我得要上班啊  -他会一直等的
-I have to work.  -He will wait.
-这次旅程怎么样?  -不错
-How was your flight?  -Good.
多谢
Thanks.
-有什么问题吗?  -你得要和我们走一趟了
-Is something wrong?  -You'll have to come with us.
你一定在开玩笑 我一个月要经过这里二次
You're kidding. I come through here twice a month.
请跟我们来
Please follow me.
有人在等我见面呢
I'm supposed to be meeting somebody.
在我工作的内容中 有三件事最重要
In my line of work, there are three things that matter.
人 文件 还有故事
The person, the document and the story.
只要找到其中一样的真相 你就找到了所有三样的真相
Find the truth of one and you find the truth of all three.
我需要你的帮助来找出真相
I need your help finding the truth.
你认识一个叫维克多·纳沃斯基的人吗?
Do you know a man named Viktor Navorski?
是的
Yes.
你知道他为什么在这里 他从那里来吗?
Do you know why he's here and where he's from?
不 我们只是普通朋友
No. We're just friends.
你有没有注意过 在他的行李箱里一直有一个罐头
Have you noticed that he hides a can of Dry Roasted Peanuts in his bag?
那又怎么样?
So?
你认为那是什么?
What do you make of that?
我猜那是花生酱
I'd make peanut butter, I guess.
我们只知道他计划去列克星敦的罗玛达酒店
We know that he's planning to go to the Ramada Inn on Lexington.
他告诉过你为什么他要来纽约吗?
Has he told you why he's in New York?
不知道
No.
他告诉过你他住那里吗?
Has he told you where he lives?
没有 我们只是在机场遇见而已
No. We just met at the airport.
我只知道他是个建筑承包商 整日带着个手提箱奔波
All I know is that he's a building contractor, living out of a suitcase.
这就是了
That's it.
-他是个承包商?  -是的
-He's a contractor?  -Yeah.
是他这么和你说得?
That's what he said?
阿米莉亚 我只是很好奇
Amelia. I'm just curious.
你是那种什么样的男人都可以得到的女人
You are the kind of woman who can get any guy she wants.
为什么选维克多·纳沃斯基?
Why Viktor Navorski?
你这种人是永远理解不了的
That's something a guy like you could never understand.
我猜你又错过你的航班了 或者你选的旅行社太差
I guess you missed your flight again. Or maybe you have a bad travel agent.
请坐
Please. Sit.
没事 维克多 所有的男人都会撒谎
It's OK, Viktor. All men lie.
-只是你不擅长撒谎  -我没有撒谎
-At least you're not very good at it.  -I did not lie.
你告诉我你被耽搁在机场了 但你从来没告诉我有9个月
You told me you were delayed. You never said it was for nine months.
或许你看男人总是一厢情愿
Maybe you see the man the way you want see the man.
那我看见的是什么? 你到底是谁?
So what am I seeing? Who are you?
-我  -不被接受?
-I...  -Unacceptable?
是的 是的
Yes. Yes.
你想听听最有趣的部分吗?
You want to hear the funny part?
我和他分手了
I broke up with him.
我来这里告诉你 他已经和我的生活无关了
I was coming here to tell you he's out of my life.
我自由了 我已经厌倦了等待
I'm free. I got tired of waiting.
至少这点我们相同
At least we have that in common.
阿米莉亚 你知道拿破仑征服巴伐利亚后
Amelia, you know what Napoleon give to…
给了约瑟芬什么礼物吗?
…Josephine when he win Bavaria?
不知道
No.
我带你去看
I show you.
请 请
Please. Please.
请坐
Sit. Please.
那就是拿破仑送给约瑟芬的礼物
That was gift. Napoleon to Josephine.
一千座喷泉
One thousand fountains.
你为我造了这个?
You built this for me?
请坐下 不要被弄湿了
Please. Sit. Don't get wet.
给点面子
Come on.
没反应了
It no work.
应该有水一直喷到天花板才对
It should shoot, big water up to ceiling.
告诉我真相吧 你是从精神病院逃出来的?
Just tell me the truth. Did you escape from an institution?
你是个罪犯吗?
Are you a criminal?
你住在这里 维克多
You're living here, Viktor.
你住在67号门 我只想知道为什么
You're living at Gate 67. I just want to know why.
这里 我给你看
Here. I show you.
我的父亲
My father.
维克多 不要告诉我你父亲在那个罐子里
Viktor, please tell me your father isn't in that peanut can.
里面是爵士
This is jazz.
我的父亲 迪麦特·阿森洛夫·纳沃斯基
My father, Dimitar Asenov Navorski,
1958年在这张匈牙利报纸上看到了一副照片
see this photograph in Hungarian newspaper 1958.
他说他整整看了这张照片有7天
He say he look at photograph for seven days.
周一 周二 周三
Monday, Tuesday, Wednesday...
他们都是谁?
Who are they?
贝西伯爵 迪齐 吉勒斯比 瑟隆尼斯 孟克 桑尼 罗林斯
Count Basie, Dizzy Gillespie, Thelonious Monk, Sonny Rollins,
亚特布雷基 马克斯 凯米斯基
Art Blakey, Max Kaminsky.
一共有57个人
57 of them all together.
在整整看了相片7天之后 我的父亲有了个主意
After looking at photograph for seven days, my father has idea.
他开始给那些俱乐部写信
He begin to write letters to club, Lickety Split, Snookie's Sugar Bowl.
他央求修女为他用英文写了几百封信
He ask the nuns to write English. Hundreds letters.
然后他就等着
And then he wait.
他就这么一星期 一月 一年的等下去
He wait month, week, year.
我的父亲等了整整40年
My father wait 40 year.
他们全都签上了名字
And they all sign names.
一个接一个
One by one.
他们都签下自己的名字 并寄给我父亲
They all write their name and send it to my father.
只有一个人除外
All but not one.
班尼·高尔森
Benny Golson.
萨克斯
Saxophone.
还没有得到班尼·高尔森的签名 我父亲就去世了
My father die before Benny Golson write his name and send to my father.
所以我给了他一个承诺 我会遵守我的承诺
So I make him promise. I keep promise.
我承诺他我会去纽约 找到班尼·高尔森
I promise I will go New York, find Benny Golson,
得到他的签名并放进这个罐头里
have him write name to put in can.
你住在这里就是为了完成你父亲的遗愿?
And you've been living here so you could do this for your father?
我现在想他这么做也是在帮我的忙
Maybe I think he do it for me.
你说你总是在等待着什么
You say you are waiting for something.
我对你说  是的  我们都在等待
And I say to you, "Yes, yes. We all wait".
那你在等什么呢?
What are you waiting for?
你 我一直在等你
You. I wait for you.
怎么了?
What?
战争已经结束了
The war is over.
绑架了总统的右翼武装
... the right-wing military coup that ousted President Vagobagin...
好的 各位 让我们举杯
All right, everybody. Let's raise your glasses.
让我们为我的朋友 维克多"山羊"干杯
Let's have a toast to my friend, Viktor "The Goat".
希望他不会再一次失去他的国家
May he never lose his country again.
卡科日亚!
Krakozhia!
阿米莉亚! 你来得真早!
Amelia! You here early!
你好 阿米莉亚 看
Hello. Amelia, look.
和平 战争已经结束 和平来了
Peace, peace in the war. The war, peace. Come.
看 战争 卡科日亚的 战争已经结束了
See, the war, the war Krakozhia is over.
和平 战争结束了
Peace. The war is over.
-你知道我在华盛顿有些朋友  -是的 是的
-You know my friend in Washington.  -Yes, yes.
他有不少关系 看这里
He has a lot of connections. Here.
这是一张通行证 维克多
It's a pass, Viktor.
紧急情况旅行签证 上面有你的名字
A one-day travel emergency visa with your name on it.
-什么 签证?  -是的
-Wha... Visa?  -Yes.
-你朋友给的?  -是的
-From your friend?  -Yeah.
去纽约吧 找到最后那个人 把他的名字放进罐子里
Just go to New York, find that last name and put it in the can.
-我去纽约?  -是的
-I go New York?  -Yes.
我要去纽约了!
I go New York!
阿米莉亚 你和我 你和我一起去纽约
Amelia, you come with. You come with me to New York.
你的朋友为我搞了这个? 为什么他要帮我?
Your friend do this for me? Why he do this for me?
他是帮我
He did it for me.
我告诉过你不要接近我 维克多 但是 你还是不明白
I told you to stay away from me, Viktor. But you didn't understand.
-我知道你会有点糊涂  -不 什么事情我都够糊涂的
-I think you were confused.  -No, I confused about everything.
但是这件事 我是十分清楚的
I not confused... Not this. Not this.
我很抱歉 我要迟到了
I'm sorry. I'm running late.
阿米莉亚 为什么你要走? 为什么你要走?
Amelia. Why you go? Why you go?
你知道当拿破仑和约瑟芬结婚的时候 他给了她什么礼物?
You know what Napoleon gave Josephine as a wedding present?
一个金子做的小盒子
It was a gold locket.
在盒子里面 他刻了一个字
And on the inside, he made an inscription.
"命运"
"Destiny".
命运
Destiny.
在大街和酒馆里到处都是庆祝的
... rejoice in the streets as well as in their local taverns.
卡克日亚的国旗已经从国会大厦换掉
The Krakozhian flag waved goodbye from high atop the parliament buildings.
现在清楚的表明
It is a clear sign of the power...
-宝贝  -嗨
-Hey, baby.  -Hi.
我很想你
I missed you.
来吧
Come on.
下一个
Next.
维克多
Viktor.
你好 德洛丽丝 今天我运气怎么样?
Hello, Delores. How I am today?
看看你带来了什么?
What do you have here?
喔 不 这还没有被签字
Oh, no. It's not signed.
什么?
What?
这是为期一天的紧急情况旅行签证
This is a one-day emergency travel visa.
必须有管理官员的签字才能生效
To validate authenticity, it needs to be signed by the supervising officer.
狄克逊?
Dixon?
是的
Yes.
狄克逊
Dixon.
我们国家的战争已经结束了
The war in my country is over.
是啊 我知道 恭喜你
Yeah. I know. Congratulations.
真是很奇怪 不是吗 维克多?
It's strange, isn't it, Viktor?
当你为一件事情等待很久之后
When you wait so long for one thing?
却在一瞬间就发生了
One tiny moment.
今天我也有了那个瞬间
I had that moment today, too.
你看到这个徽章了吗?
You see this badge?
这个徽章表示我已经成为了海关边境保护局地区委任专员
This badge means that I was made CBP Field Commissioner.
它意味着我对这个机场有绝对的控制权
It means that my authority over the security of this airport is absolute.
你的护照和机票
Your ticket and your passport.
到了你该回家的时候了
It's time for you to go home.
威林长官 请带纳沃斯基先生去候机室
Officer Waylin, please show Mr Navorski into the terminal
确保他不要错过他的航班
and make sure he does not miss his flight.
再见了 维克多 祝你好运
Goodbye, Viktor, and good luck.
我想去纽约
I think I want go New York City.
别把这事复杂化了 维克多
Don't make this difficult, Viktor.
我不再是 "无法接受"的人了
I no more "unacceptable".
-我告诉过你这一切都结束了  -我要去纽约
-I told you this is over.  -I go New York.
你真的确定你要这样做吗?
Are you sure you want to do that?
我要去纽约市 现在就去
I go New York City now.
我工作的一部分就是处理不受欢迎的人 这里就有一些
Part of my job is to get rid of undesirables, and there are quite a few.
像是这个人 乔·玛洛伊 我认为你认识他
Like this guy, Joe Mulroy. I think you know him.
他已经在这里干了20多年 但是他经常下班后在这里赌博
He's been here for 20 years, but he's been running an after-hour poker game.
还带酒和大麻进入机场
Bringing in liquor and marijuana.
这个可怜的人将要失去退休金了 而且他还有几个孩子呢
Poor guy's going to lose his pension. And I think he has kids, too.
是吗
Yep.
还有这个家伙 恩里克·克鲁兹 我想你也认识吧
And then there's this guy, Enrique Cruz. I think you also know Enrique.
恩里克经常随便让人进入储藏食物的地方
Enrique has been letting people into the food preparation area.
那可是重大的安全隐患
That's a major security breach.
这个可怜的家伙 我想他才刚刚结婚吧
The poor guy, I think he's a newlywed.
但是我还是要炒他的鱿鱼
But I'm going to have to let him go.
这里还有古普塔·拉哈 他是个清扫工
And then there's Gupta Rajan. He's a janitor.
但是他由于1979年在 印度袭击一个警察被通缉
But he's wanted for assaulting a police officer back in India in 1979.
我将不得不遣返他
I'll have to deport him.
我会回家去的
I will go home.
-对不起 你说什么?  -我会回家去
-I'm sorry. What did you say?  -I will go home.
别碰他们 我会走的
Leave them alone. I will go.
-就今天  -是的
-Today.  -Yes.
如果你没有上那班飞机 他们都得走
If you don't get on that plane, they're all gone.
-你懂了吗?  -是的
-Do you understand?  -Yes.
好的 不错
OK. Good.
请大家注意了
Your attention please.
搭乘加拿大航空公司往渥太华309号班机的旅客
Immediate boarding, gate B-20, for flight…
请立即到B-20门登机
…number 309 Air Canada to Ottawa.
我不敢相信你
I don't believe you.
-维克多 你不必这样做的  -你可以和这些家伙们斗争
-Viktor, you don't have to do this.  -You can fight these guys.
-我们都会帮你的  -维克多 别这样 我欠你太多了
-We'll help you.  -Viktor, come on. I owe you so much.
-求你让我帮你把  -这是你朋友的忠告
-Please let me help you.  -This is your friend talking.
我们都是你的朋友 我们现在都是你的家人
We're all your friends. We're your family now.
古普塔
Gupta.
再见
Goodbye.
你想愚弄我们吗
You try to fool us.
你让我们相信你会走出这里 相信你会和他们做斗争
You make us to think you would walk out, that you will fight with them.
你为什么不做斗争?
Why don't you fight?
-战争已经结束了  -那么走吧 从这里消失
-The war is over.  -Then go. Get lost.
从这里消失 回你的家去并告诉他们你没有成功
Get lost. Go home and tell them you never made it.
你曾经离美国只有这么点距离
You come this close to America,
但是你从这里到 这里的勇气都没有
but you don't have the courage to go from here to here.
你是个孬种
You are a coward.
飞机就要起飞了
The plane is on time.
你是个孬种
You are a coward.
You are a coward!
你让我恶心!
You make me sick!
你到底是怎么了 伙计? 消消气
What's wrong with you, man? Settle down.
让周围的人都看着我 好像我是
Got people looking all around, looking at me like I'm... [sighs]
看着我
Look at me.
来吧 看着我
Come on, look at me.
有些事你应该知道
There's something you should know.
先生们女士们 从卡科日亚来的
Ladies and gentlemen, United Airlines Flight 865
联合航空的865航班已经降落 正在前往闸门
from Krakozhia has landed and is now taxiing to the gate.
乘坐866航班前往卡科日亚的乘客们
For those passengers holding tickets for Flight 866 to Krakozhia,
希望你们能按时登机
we expect departure to be on schedule.
后退 麻烦你
Get back, please.
古普塔
Gupta.
古普塔!
Gupta!
我要回家了
I am going home.
快走吧
Get lost.
请注意
Your attention, please.
前往卡科日亚的866航班 将推迟起飞 请敬待进一步通知
Flight 866 to Krakozhia will be delayed until further notice.
你们有预约吗?
Do you have an appointment?
谁能告诉我下面他妈的 到底发生了什么事!
Somebody tell me what the hell is going on down there!
我们就背后支持你
We're right behind you.
维克多正在离开这里
Viktor's leaving.
-莫尼卡 维克多正在离开  -我知道 他要回家了
-Monica, Viktor's leaving.  -I know. He's going home.
他正在朝正门走 要进入纽约市了
He's going for the front door, out to the city.
什么?
What?
维克多 要记得我们啊
Viktor. Remember us.
我是"探索"专卖店的 我想要送你这个
From the Discovery Store, I want to give you this.
它会带给你好运
It's good luck.
这是库辛·凯忒雅店送你的数码照相机
A digital camera for cousin Katia.
我不知道你要去那里 但是这东西能让你的脚暖和些
I don't know where you're going, but these will keep your feet warm.
-全体都到位了?  -我们都到了
-Everybody in position?  -We're here.
看住门口
Secure the door.
对不起 维克多
Sorry, Viktor.
抓住他 乔治
Take him, Judge.
站住 维克多 放松点
Hold it, Viktor. Take it easy.
你看到这些门了吗?
You see those doors?
那些门是纽约市的入口
Those are the entry doors to New York City.
前往美利坚合众国的入口 转过去
To the United States of America. Turn around.
城里正在下雪 你需要这个
It's snowing in the city and you're going to need that.
祝你好运
Good luck.
喔 不 喔 不 喔 不
Oh, no. Oh, no. Oh, no. Oh, no.
不要 不要 不要
Oh, no. Oh, no. No, no.
我会想你的
I'm going to miss you.
不管你去那里 记得别再被困住了
Try not to get stuck wherever you're going.
逮住他! 逮住他!
Arrest him! Arrest him!
该死的!
Goddammit!
出租车!
Taxi!
多谢
Thank you.
去那里?
Where you go?
列克星敦161号 请走范华克高速到皇后大桥
161 Lexington. Please take Van Wyck Expressway to Queensboro Bridge.
比走布鲁伦至皇后高速要快很多
It's faster than BQE.
-你从那里来的?  -卡科日亚 维克多·纳沃斯基
-Where you from?  -Krakozhia. Viktor Navorski.
我是戈伦 阿尔巴尼亚人
I'm Goran. Albania.
-你是什么时候来纽约的?  -周四
-When do you come to New York?  -Thursday.
你要封锁住南面的出口 并检查每一辆汽车吗?
You want us to block the south exit and have AP sweep every vehicle?
长官?
Sir?
从东京来的530航班已经降落了
5.30 from Tokyo just landed.
停机坪上有二架飞机 去巴塞罗那的那架正要降落
Got two planes on the tarmac. Barcelona on approach.
这个夜晚才刚刚开始 还有1500个乘客等着服务呢
The night is young and 1500 people are headed our way.
大家都进去吧 大家都进去吧
Everybody inside. Everybody inside.
来吧 我们走
Come on, let's go.
我们走
Let's go.
-先生 你要入住吗?  -不 不 我不需要
-Are you checking in, sir?  -No, no. I don't check in.
我想要去这个地方
I want to go to this place, please.
大厅酒吧 就在拐角的地方
The lobby lounge is around the corner.
那里有现场音乐会 你喜欢爵士乐吗?
They have happy hour specials and live music. Do you like jazz?
扬声器已经关掉了
The monitor's off.
钢琴没问题 再多一点贝斯 贝斯声音再大一点
The piano's OK. A little more bass. More bass from the monitor.
让我们来演奏Killer Joe  昨晚很受欢迎
Let's do Killer Joe. It worked all right last night.
-什么事?  -你就是班尼·高尔森?
-Yes?  -You are Benny Golson?
是的 是的 我就是
Yeah. Yes, I am.
班尼·高尔森 我叫维克多·纳沃斯基 我从卡科日亚来
Benny Golson, I am Viktor Navorski. I am from Krakozhia.
我的父亲迪麦特·阿森洛夫·纳沃斯基 他十分喜爱你的音乐
My father, Dimitar Asenov Navorski, was great, great fan of your music.
爵士乐迷 太好了
A jazz fan. Fantastic.
请问你能在这里签名吗?
Would you sign your name, please?
等等一会儿吗? 我们正要开始演奏呢
Can I do it a little later? We have to get started now.
-只要几分钟  -我会等的
-Just a minute.  -I will wait.
好的
OK.
出租车! 出租车!
Taxi! Taxi!
你想要去那儿?
Where you want to go?
我要回家啦
I am going home.